ERNEST, ANYEWE ADONU

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER

adonuernest@gmail.com | GitHub | LinkedIn | Twitter | AngelList | Medium | Portfolio

SUMMARY

Skilled software engineer with more than 1000 hours of teamwork in JavaScript, React, Redux, Bootstrap, SCSS, CSS, PostgreSQL, Ruby, and Rails. Skilled at producing top-notch web apps with a heavy emphasis on effectiveness and user experience.

SKILLS

Front-End: JavaScript, Typescript, React, Redux, Bootstrap, HTML5, CSS3

Back-End: Ruby, Rails, PostgreSQL

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Heroku, Netlify, Mobile/Responsive Development, RSpec, TDD, Chrome Dev

Tools

Professional: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring

EXPERIENCE

HIGHLIGHTED PERSONAL PROJECTS

Remote

Full Stack Web Development Student & Mentor

May 2022 - February 2023

Mastered intermediate and advanced topics in full-stack development (including React, Rails, Git, and DS&A challenges) while building multiple full-stack projects independently and via pair programming.

<u>Awesome Book</u> — Collaborated on a library-like project where users can add books to the shelf (object array) and keep a record of books read without memorizing them.

Built with: (JavaScript, HTML, CSS, and Bootstrap) <u>Live Demo</u>

<u>Lavish Cuisine</u> — Collaborated on a meal-based website that gives users all the information they need about their favorite breakfast, lunch, and dinner depending on the selected country.

Built with: (react-typescript, redux, and CSS) <u>Live Demo</u>

<u>Trek Bike Rentals</u> — Collaborated on a rental web app where users can reserve, add delete a bike of their choice.

• Built with: (Ruby on Rails, React-Redux, and CSS) Live Demo

MICROVERSE Remote

Mentor (Volunteer)

July 2022 - December 2022

- Mentored two junior web developers and provided technical support through code reviews.
- Proposed improvements to code organisation to improve code quality and overall performance.
- Provided my mentees with advice and tips on maintaining motivation for longevity in the program.

ISON EXPERIENCES Accra, Ghana

Customer Service Executive

September 2020 – January 2022

- Motivated the team to meet its set target and won the team of the month award in June 2021.
- Resolved an average of 200 customer complaints each day with 98% satisfied with the service.

EDUCATION

MICROVERSE May 2022 – February 2023

Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full Time

- Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux
- Developed skills in remote pair programming using GitHub, industry-standard git-flow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

GHANA COMMUNICATION TECHNOLOGY UNIVERSITY (GCTU)

Degree in Computer Engineering

January 2021 - December 2022

• Obtained my Bachelor's Degree in Computer engineering.

KOFORIDUA TECHNICAL UNIVERSITY (KTU)

Higher National Diploma in Electrical/Electronic Engineering

September 2015 - June 2018

• Obtained my HND in Electrical/Electronic Engineering (GPA: 4.05).